<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>computational-spacetime on Domain Flow Architecture</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/tags/computational-spacetime/index.html</link><description>Recent content in computational-spacetime on Domain Flow Architecture</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/tags/computational-spacetime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spacetime</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/spacetime/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/spacetime/index.html</guid><description>Constraints of Spacetime If you try to visualize the &amp;lsquo;world&amp;rsquo; from the perspective of an operand flowing through a machine, you realize that a physical machine creates a specific spatial constraint for the movement of program and data. Processing nodes are fixed in space, and information is exchanged between nodes to accomplish some transformation; we have nodes to generate operands and communication lanes between the nodes to send operands (or programs) around.</description></item><item><title>Computational Spacetime</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/computational-spacetime/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/computational-spacetime/index.html</guid><description>Computational Spacetime Data movement in a parallel machine experiences the constraints of spacetime and more. The propagation delays in the communication channels act similarly as the constraint on the speed of light in spacetime. Let&amp;rsquo;s bring back the mental model of a parallel machine being a fixed graph in space with communication channels connecting a subset of nodes. The channels of communication constrain the propagation directions for information exchange. If we make the assumption that computation and communication are separate steps and that they can be overlapped to hide the latency of the communication phase, then we can leverage the mental model of spacetime to argue about partial orders of computational events that might be able to effect each other.</description></item></channel></rss>