<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>computational-spacetime on Domain Flow Architecture</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/tags/computational-spacetime/index.html</link><description>Recent content in computational-spacetime on Domain Flow Architecture</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/tags/computational-spacetime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Constraints of Spacetime</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/spacetime/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/spacetime/index.html</guid><description>If you visualize the &amp;lsquo;world&amp;rsquo; from the perspective of an operand flowing through a machine, you realize that a physical machine creates a specific spatial constraint for the movement of data. Processing nodes are fixed in space, and information is exchanged between nodes to accomplish some transformation. Nodes consume and generate information, and communication links move information (program and data) between nodes. This leads to a simple abstraction of a physical parallel machine consisting of a fixed graph in space that constraints computation and communication events generated by the parallel algorithm.</description></item><item><title>Computational Spacetime</title><link>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/computational-spacetime/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 06:58:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stillwater-sc.github.io/domain-flow/introduction/computational-spacetime/index.html</guid><description>Data movement in a parallel machine is constrained by propagation delay. The propagation delay in a communication channel acts similarly as the constraint on the speed of light in spacetime. Think back to the model of a physical parallel machine being a fixed graph in space with communication channels connecting computational nodes. The channels of communication constrain the propagation directions for information exchange. To enable fine-grain parallelism assume that computation and communication are separate steps in a computational even.</description></item></channel></rss>